Kedar Krishnan

116, 10 Ronayne street, Auckland Central, Auckland 1010

E: kedar.krishnan@gmail.com M: 027 431 5111

SUMMARY

I am a full stack developer with 12+ years of experience across banking, finance and telecom domain. My expertise lies in working on projects using Java, Spring, JavaScript, AngularJS, NodeJS, CSS, BIRT and Restful web services.

I'm an active proponent of Object oriented programming – I love the power of encapsulating the implementation details using Java classes and JavaScript objects, and the way restful services integrate the backend with the frontend.

My personal development project includes a content management system using Spring Boot, Java 8, restful web services for backend, and Angular JS for frontend.

SKILLS

Java

Spring Framework

I have experience of using spring's web-MVC, transaction management and Spring AOP, scheduling, batch. I have exposure to spring annotations and in my opinion annotation helps you in faster development but great care needs to be taken with naming conversion and packaging to make code review and maintenance easy.

Testing

Most general testing I have approached with Junit. EasyMock usually supplements my Junit tests because it provides an easy way for replacement of a collaborator object. I have used Eclipse plugin EclEmma to identify areas of more attention when extending test suites, but in my experience, chasing test coverage numbers leads to brittle tests.

Front-End

I have excellent experience with JavaScript. JavaScript's prototype-based inheritance model is a little unusual, as are its block-scoping rules. I have used jQuery and AngularJS commercially and have recently started dabbling RxJS with in my free time.

Other Skills

I would be happy to discuss my commercial experience with and exposure to: Agile SCRUM, MySQL, Bootstrap, NodeJS, BIRT.

OPEN SOURCE AND COMMUNITY

infoGraph.js

A JavaScript charting module, used for displaying profile skills infograph on web page.

indian-states-cities

A NodeJS module for getting states and cities of India based on criteria.

Participated in GovHack 2016 Auckland. Awarded "Voted best embodiment of the Sprint of GovHack for amazing team work" http://2016.hackerspace.govhack.org/content/ptp

My web page: http://kedarkrishnan.github.io/

My github page https://github.com/kedarkrishnan

WORK EXPERIENCE

Associate - Developer JP MORGAN; Oct 2008 - Jun 2016

Skills used: Java, Spring, BIRT, SCRUM, Git, Bootstrap, JavaScript, AngularJS, JQuery

Role overview: Senior Developer helping to design and architect a reporting engine using open source BIRT. Working closely with US counter parts, vendor teams, allocating and reviewing work done by team members. Originally employed to help build reports using licensed Actuate BIRT and parsing the data from a web service.

Interesting challenges: Working from Chicago office for two months to create framework on Java to expedite report development on BIRT reporting tool.

Migrating from licensed Actuate BIRT to open source BIRT saving around 2 million US\$ per year required creation of wrappers around BIRT runtime using Spring so as to add more functionalities like administration, web service support, scheduling and storage.

Building interactive functionality on reports using Bootstrap, Javascript and Jquery so that users can change the structure of the reports at runtime.

Analyst Programmer SYNTEL; Jan 2006 – Oct 2008

Skills used: Java, Spring, CSS, HTML, JavaScript, JQuery

Role overview: Designing and development of customizable portal for displaying dashboard for Syntel's Center of Excellence team. Work on projects from different clients like State Street, Wells Fargo. Working with clients for requirement gathering, creating technical analysis document (TAD).

Interesting challenges: Creation of Actuate COE portal, which is demoed to customers as a part of pre-sales not only needed to have dynamic functionality like customizable screens but also needed to look aesthetic.

Working for State Street from Boston, Massachusetts's office for a year developing customized reports and front end.

Developer SEEINFOBIZ; Nov 2003 – Jan 2006

Skills used: Java, JSP, HTML, JavaScript

Role overview: Designing and developing customer-billing system for Telecommunication Company.

Interesting challenges: Understanding the raw billing files to write parsers to read the data and formatting the outputs for online as well as printing for 13 circles with different billing cycles and requirements needed the system to be customizable and also efficient to generate the require bills within the estimated time.

EDUCATION QUALIFICATION

Graduate Diploma in Computing

Unitec - Auckland, New Zealand; 2016 - Current

Bachelor of Engineering

Mumbai University; 1997 - 2001